Hello friends, today's blog will be that
if you live in Delhi and if you
want to apply for a new water connection in your house or you already have an
old house and a water meter is already installed,
but if you want to get a secondary water meter
installed, then what will be its process,
today we will see that process, for that
first of all you have to
come to the website of djb.gov.in i.e. djb.gov.in, I will give you its URL
in the description box, then
after this there is Services,
after this after Services you have to click on Apply for New Connection
or Regularization option,
then after this you have to
click on the cross here, then after this
a complete form of Application Form for New Connection
opens here, that is, you have to
fill the complete form of a new connection. Z
RO Location Z RO Location is that location
where the area in which you live
and the area falls under which Z RO location of Delhi Jal Board,
you have to find out that
or if you do not know then
if someone has a water connection running next to your house
then check his bill there  If z RO
location is written then you will select that z location
here, suppose if my
root location is Janakpuri then I will select it here,
then after this the first one
is type of request, now what is there here is
water and sewerage connection, if your house is being
built completely new then you will have to
apply for water and sewerage connection,
if you already have a water connection or
sewerage connection together but if you
want to get a new meter or secondary meter installed
then you
can apply for a separate water connection here, if you
want to get a separate sewerage connection in a different way then you will have to click on sewerage connection, I already have a
water and
sewerage connection, so right now I have to
apply only for a water connection, a
secondary one, so I will have to click on water connection,
then after this here is
permanent and temporary, permanent means
that your temporary connection will continue forever, it
means that if you are getting a new
house built then what happens is that you will not need
water  If there is a requirement, then in that case,
until your house is completely built,
you need a temporary connection for that period.
Similarly,
in BSCS also, until
your house is built, you have to
remove your existing meter
and get a temporary connection installed. So, the
same case will be there here also. If you are
building a completely new house, then for some time
until your house is built,
you have to get a temporary connection installed. So,
you will have to click on Temporary Connection. But if we
apply for a permanent connection, then
we will click on Permanent Connection.
Friend, here there is an option to upload the photo.
To upload the photo,
you have to click on this edit button.
Then, after clicking on this edit button, you will
upload the format which you want to upload, you
can do it in JPG or PNG. You
can upload your photo and the size of that photo should
not be more than 1 inch.
Then, friend, you will have to fill in the first name,
middle name and last name here.
Suppose if your property
is in the name of joint owners, if you
want to get it in the name of both the persons, then
you will have to write the name of both the persons here.
Suppose under first name you
can write Sushil Kumar and under last name you
can write Pun Kumar. If the
property is in your single name, then
suppose if your name
is Sushil Kumar, then you will write Sushil Kumar here.
After this, here you will write father name
or husband name. If a female
wants to get it in her name, then you will write husband name here. In
our case, if it is in the name of a male, then
we will write our father's name here.
If you are
applying for a government organization, then we will
tick here. Otherwise, this will have to be left.
We are currently applying in the name of an individual,
so we have
nothing to do with any government department. Here
you have to give your contact email ID, mobile number and
office number. Under office number,
if you do not have a loan number, then
you can give your mobile number here.  You will have to give it
but you have to keep the mobile number and office number separate.
Fifth is for Delhi Jal Board
employee. If you are an employee within Delhi Jal Board, then
you will have to tick here and
then fill in your complete details.
Property description.
Inside the property description, you have to
fill in your address here, fill in the landmark, fill in the
pin code, then you have to
select the locality, select the sub-locality.
Suppose if my pin code is this,
I will have to fill in my pin code first,
then after this you will have to
select your locality here, then after this
you will have to select the sub-locality as well,
whichever assembly you fall under,
you will choose that assembly from here, then after this you will
select whatever word you fall under,
then after this you have to fill in your complete address here, the
save number is property and
water connection use details. Now here the first one
is property type. Property type,
you have to select what
type of property you have, so like this is
our individual house, we do
not have any commercial use, due to this we have to
select individual house here.  We have to do the number
of floors, first of all we have the grand
floor, then after that the number of floors that are
made becomes first, second, third,
so I have ground plus one, so
I will write one here, the number of beds, this is
inside the case of hospital, it
is divisible anyway, you cannot fill it, now
here you have to fill the plot area in square
meter, then under built up area,
under built up area, you can write the same size here,
water connection category, now
under water connection category, you have to
select domestic here because we will
not use any commercial water
connection, who will use it,
here you have been given to select the department,
but ours here is
individual, so we are
using it for residential purpose here, if we are
using it for domestic purpose, then we
will select residential here, then here you have to
fill the bank details, you have to fill your bank name, branch
name, FC code and bank account number,
rain water harvesting, if you
want to apply for this facility, then
here  You will have to tick Apply for
RWH, after this you will get options to fill the details,
otherwise
you will leave it because rain water
harvesting is a different thing, then there is 10th pay
document to be attached, now here you have to
attach the documents, the first one is
proof of identity, in this you will see
driving license, PAN card, passport,
ration card with applicant's photo and Aadhar
card, water ID card,
you can also upload bank passbook
if it has a photo, right now we
have a driving license,
I will select the driving license, then
after this I will fill my DL number here
and we will upload identity of
document, inside this we
can go to choose file and upload our document,
what are its conditions, you have to click on this IK button once,
then after this
you will see here, please
upload valid image, that is, you
can upload it in JPG, you
can upload it in PDF, this format has been shown to you
and its maximum file size
It should not be more than 5 AB and then
after this is the second ownership status. Now
under the ownership status, if you are the owner then you are
occupied, you are a
legal heir or there is any other condition, then you will
tick on others. Now in our case,
I am the owner, so I have to tick on owner.
After this, here you will see the
download self-declaration
form. You will have to click on it once and
download it. As soon as you download it,
then this is a kind of anr a
form. Here it is written Self
Declaration from section of new water or
sewerage connection from Delhi Jal Board.
Here it means that
you want to apply for water and sewerage connection from Delhi Jal Board.
Now you have to
fill the form here. I or V means the name of the person in whose
name you are applying for this water connection will appear.
If you are
applying for an individual name, then after
ticking I, you will write the name of the individual and
their address will appear. If this is a joint
property name, then on V  By ticking
you will write the names of the partners, then their
address, under the address you will fill only one address for
which you have to apply,
then by dragging down you have to come down, if it is a
single owner then it will be single sign, if it is a joint
owner then it will be joint sign, then you have to
fill the name, in whichever way you are applying
you have to fill the address and
contact number, after filling this you have to go to the
form again, as if you have come to this online form,
then after this
you have to go to choose file and upload it, then
after this the next option is property ownership, now
what is there here, they have to show the electricity
bill in the name of the applicant,
you have to show the last three bills, but what is that
I had uploaded it but the
Delhi Electricity Board people had rejected it,
they said that you have to
show the proof of complete ownership, so for this you have to show whatever
property you have, suppose if
you have taken this property through registered sale deed
or you have lease deed, conveyance deed,
you have GPA, so whatever it is  You
will select it, suppose if I
have a registered GPA then I will
select it, then after this any GPA comes as
a stamp paper, it gets
generated online, its
ID is used as a series, you have to
fill its serial number here, then you have to
upload the entire chain of your registered property here, keep in mind that
inside the registered deed, be it a registered GPA
or a registered sale deed or a registered lease
deed, whatever ownership is shown,
you have to upload the entire chain here starting from here
and its maximum file
size should not be more than 5 AB
and inside the property ownership document, that
is, you have to fill the document number here,
that document number will
start with ID & DL, then after this there is
Others option, you can choose
that if you want to take NOC from someone,
suppose if you have a joint
property, like I have this
property, it is in the name of me and my brother,
if I am in the name of my brother  If I get an NOC from him and
apply for my Delhi connection in a single name, then that is possible, for that
you will have to get the NOC written on a stamp paper and it should be
notarized, you can get it for a value of ₹10
and after signing the stamp, the
notary will give it to you, then
after this your original signature is there,
after scanning it you will have to
upload it here and inside the other document
you have to fill the document number,
inside this document number also you have to
fill the entire series of the notary's I NDL,
if you have any old NOC which used to
come on stamp paper earlier, then you can download it online in today's date,
but in the old
times it used to come in printed form, so the
series which you have, you have to fill it here,
then after this friend you have to drag down and
come down, after this here on
Submitted by cell by default click on
Upload Signature, then your signature will be
uploaded here, then here you will have to fill the caption,
then you will tick on the I Agree button
Then after this you have to click on the preview button,
as you will see the entire preview,
if everything is fine then you have to
click on the submit button, as soon as your
form is submitted then the
application reference number gets generated to you
and the name of the person in whose name you are applying is
visible here
and whatever was the built up area,
you get to see the date on which
you submitted it,
then after this you get two options together,
Acknowledgement Received and Download
Feed Application Form, you have to
download both of these and keep them for future reference,
friend, as soon as you submit the form,
if you want to check the status of the error number or reference number that has come to you, then
you have to
go to information for that and then after this
you have to click on track application status,
then after this here under Ear and
Type, if you had applied for a new connection then
you have to select on new connection, then you have to fill the Ear number
which was your reference number,
then after this you  After filling the captcha,
click on the search button. As soon as
you click on the search button, your error
number will be displayed, which will be under process. You have to
check this because your form has been
submitted successfully or not. For example,
we first applied for a
new water connection on the Delhi Jal Board website. As soon as
we apply,
we receive an ERN number.
After receiving that ERN number, your document
goes for document verification. There is
a complete document verification team
which audits your uploaded document.
They will audit your document within two days i.e. within 48 hours.
Keep in mind that 48 hours will be within your working
days only. If you
upload it on Sunday, then obviously it will not be audited on that day.
As soon as your document is verified, then
after this your side visit takes place.
Friend, if your document is
verified, only then will your side verification take place.
Otherwise, if your side
verification has not been done, it means
that your documents have been rejected.
You will also get a message informing you
that your document has been rejected. If
you do not get the status in the message, then
you can check it from the ARM status check that I just told you, from
which region your document has been rejected. If
you resubmit your application on the basis of that region, then
you will get a new ARM number.
Suppose that if your document has been
verified and your side visit will be done,
it will be done within 48 hours, that is, as soon as the
documents are verified,
your side visit will be done within two to three days.
After that, you have to wait for 15 days like your
side visit because the side
verification officer comes to your house,
he checks your dimensions and goes away and after
seeing your house, he decides whether you are
applying for a fresh or a repeat visit.  If
you are applying for a connection, then
he checks all your things and will
definitely take your house name here.
After this, you have to wait for 15 days. The
day of the side visit is a
standard time period within which you have to
wait. Before this, your ARN will
not be generated because the side verification
officer submits your report to the Consent JR
location. As soon as 15 days are
completed, everything is fine.
After this, you get the
option of ARN successfully submitted and
your CANO number is generated. Here
you will see, dear consumer, your
new connection application, which is your ARN number,
you will see it here. It has been processed
successfully, that is, the ARN
number for the new connection has been
processed successfully and your
CANO number is this.
You will get this message from Delhi Jal Board
and you can check its status by going to your ARN status.
Friend, suppose
if you have ARN  If you want to check the status, then
for this, after knowing the information here, you have to go to
Track Application Status,
friend, here you have to
select New Connection under Ern Type, fill the error number,
after filling the capture, you have to
click on the search button, so friend, here
you can see the
name of the applicant, the address of the applicant,
application status, if yours has been approved then
only you will be able to see the complete status here,
if it is rejected then it will
appear as rejected here, after dragging down a little here,
you will
see below that your application has been
approved, is active and
your cano number has been generated,
friend, as you get the message of cano number generation,
it means that
you have got a new cano number i.e. new water number
and some
fee is charged according to your area,
you have to pay that fee online, to make online payment,
first of all you have to download your bill, to
download the bill,
drag down and come down, view
print latest bill, you have to click on it
After this, after filling in your new CAN number,
you have to
fill in the captcha here and then click on view bill. As
soon as you click,
a bill will be generated in PDF.
Here it will show your name,
address, mobile number,
your zone area and location will be shown to
you. The CAN number will be shown to you.
Friend, here it will also show you the charges
that your house falls under which area
and your
water meter charge is levied according to the location. This is
not a security amount that whenever you get
it released i.e. removed, you will
get a refund. It is not like that, you have to make the payment
and you should forget about it. You do
not get any security benefit on this. So
friend, as soon as you see the
complete details here that this CAN number has been
passed in your name only and is at your address only.
If everything is fine, then
you will copy the CAN number. After copying the CAN number,
you have to click on the Pay Online button.
After this, you have to click on Pay through Payment Gateway.
Then
after filling the CAN number, after clicking on Get Details,
you have to fill the captcha, so here
you will get a form to make the payment,
you have to make the payment then friend, as soon as you make the
payment,
you get to see the acknowledgement slip of the payment, friend, the
water meter charge at my place was
₹1, so I have made the payment successfully,
I get the acknowledgement of successful payment, as the
team comes to you after 15 days,
they will first ask you on call whether
you have a new house or an old house
because they will come accordingly, if
boring is also to be done at your house, then they will
also call the boring team, they will bore under your house
and then will install the water meter at your house and go away,
you have to keep in mind that if
you have an old house and already have a water meter
and sewerage connection, then if they
come again to install the water meter, then
they do not install the meter and go away, they say
that it is the work of a plumber, the same thing happened with me
that I had installed the second  I applied for the meter
because I already had a water meter
installed and the fitting was already done.
When they came, they told me that
they would not install the water meter and I would have to get it done
by a plumber. So, they gave me the
meter and I got it installed, friend.
This was the complete process of how we
can apply for a new water meter in Delhi. Thank you friend.